Every generation has its hero. Meet ours.
Just Mercy is a drama, crime, history film directed by Destin Daniel Cretton.
The powerful true story of Harvard-educated lawyer Bryan Stevenson, who goes to Alabama to defend the disenfranchised and
wrongly condemned — including Walter McMillian, a man sentenced to death despite evidence proving his innocence.
Bryan fights tirelessly for Walter with the system stacked against them.
Bryan Stevenson, played by Michael B. Jordan.
Eva Ansley, played by Brie Larson.
Walter McMillian, played by Jamie Foxx.
Anthony Ray Hinton, played by O'Shea Jackson Jr..
Tommy Champan, played by Rafe Spall.
Herbert Richardson, played by Rob Morgan.
Just Mercy is a 2019 American biographical legal drama film co-written and
directed by Destin Daniel Cretton and starring Michael B.
Jordan as Bryan Stevenson, Jamie Foxx as Walter McMillian, Rob
Morgan, Tim Blake Nelson, Rafe Spall, and Brie Larson.
It explores the work of young defense attorney Bryan Stevenson who
represents poor people on death row in the South.
Featured is his work with Walter McMillian, who had been
wrongfully convicted of the murder of a young woman.
The film is based on Stevenson's 2014 eponymous memoir, in which he explored his
journey to making his life's work the defense of African American prisoners.
Just Mercy, which had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film
Festival on September 6, 2019, was theatrically released by Warner Bros.
Pictures on December 25, 2019.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed $50 million.
Foxx was nominated for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a
Supporting Role at the 26th Screen Actors Guild Awards.
Both he and Michael B.
Jordan won NAACP Image Awards for their respective roles.
The film explores themes of death penalty, judge,
innocence, based on true story, lawyer.
The tone is emotional.